mention.com 2018-02-09

# What is Mention's Privacy Policy? - Mention Knowledge Base

Mention Solutions is committed to safeguarding the Personal Data of Users. This privacy policy (“ **Privacy Policy** ”) is part of the [ToS](https://en.support.mention.com/article/443-terms-of-service). Each word defined in the [ToS](https://en.support.mention.com/article/443-terms-of-service) has the same meaning in the Privacy Policy.

By using the Services, Users agree to abide and be bound by this Privacy Policy, which may be modified or updated from time to time without notice. In this event the update will be displayed on Mention Solutions’ websites.

  * **Nature of Personal Data Collected by Mention Solutions**

Mention Solutions collects and processes data that Users voluntarily provide in order to access or use its Services and data related to Users’ preferences and traffic (such as IP addresses). 

The purposes of this data processing are to enable Users to create an Account for accessing the Services, constantly improve the Services, and send commercial offers to Users. 

Users need to open an Account and provide Mention Solutions with at least the following personally identifiable data to use the Services:

  * Name;

  * Email address;

  * Company name.

Users may complete their profile with other Personal Data (their address, etc.).

Mention Solutions will never collect or process Personal Data pertaining to, directly or indirectly, race, health, sexual orientation, political, philosophical, or religious views.

  * **Non-Personal Identifiable Data & Cookies**

**_2.1. Traffic_**

Traffic data are generated when Users’ terminals connect to the internet and are not sufficient alone to identify them. Mention Solutions may collect the following data: origin of the connection, type and version of Users internet browser, length of connection, etc. 

Such data may be used for statistical purposes to analyze the traffic and to improve the Services. Traffic data are always processed anonymously. 

**_2.2. Cookies_**

Mention Solutions places cookies on Users’ terminals. These small files may contain, for instance, traffic data and Users’ preferences. 

The purposes of the cookies placed by Mention Solutions are to:

  * authenticate Users (session ID cookies);

  * record Users’ visits and activities and to restore their web pages in order to enable certain features of the Services or Mention Solutions’ websites;

  * send targeted commercial offers to Users.

Mention Solutions authorizes its partners to place cookies on Users’ terminals to collect Users’ data for marketing and statistical purposes.

Cookies are mandatory to use some the Services and consequently must be accepted by Users. Users can configure their browser to disable cookies or to prompt them before accepting a cookie from the websites they visit.  If Users disable cookies, however, they may not be able to use all portions of Mention Solutions’ websites or all functionalities of the Services.

  * **Processing of Users’ Personal Data**

Mention Solutions collects and processes Users’ Personal Data in a fair and lawful manner and in respect of their rights. Mention Solutions is the entity responsible for processing Users’ Personal Data. 

The processing of Users’ Personal Data made by Mention Solutions is registered with the French Registrar: _“Commission Nationale de l’Informatique et des Libertés”_ (CNIL).

  * **Retention of Users’ Personal Data**

**_4\. 1. Security_**

The Personal Data that Users communicate to Mention Solutions are hosted by Mention Solutions. Mention Solutions uses its best efforts to prevent any interference with Users’ Personal Data such as loss, diversion, intrusion, unauthorized divulgation, alteration, or destruction. 

**_4\. 2. Term_**

Without prejudice to the following paragraph, the Personal Data processed by Mention Solutions will be deleted three (3) months after the cancellation of Users Account.

Mention Solutions is under duty keeping during one (1) year the following Personal Data as from the creation, change or deletion of Users Content:

  * Identifier of connection;

  * Identifier given by the computer;

  * Types of protocols;

  * Nature of the operation;

  * Date and hour of the operation;

  * Identifier used by the author of the operation.

**_4.3. Cancellation of Account_**

Users may request that their Account be cancelled pursuant to the ToS. Their data will be deleted by Mention Solutions without prejudice to section 4.2 above.

  * **Communication from Mention Solutions**

Mention Solutions may send emails to Users to the address associated with their account for technical or administrative purposes or to inform Users of the evolution of its Service. Mention Solutions will not send Users commercial offers unrelated to Mention Solutions. 

Mention Solutions will never send to Users commercial email if they refused to receive it.

  * **Transfer of Users’ Personal Data**

Mention Solutions undertakes not to share Users’ Personal Data with or transfer them to third parties unless they have consented prior to said sharing or transfer. Mention Solutions will never share Users personal data with third parties that do not guarantee an adequate protection. 

Mention Solutions may provide Users’ Personal Data if required by law or compelled by a court of law.

  * **Right to Access, Modify and Delete Users’ Personal Data**

Pursuant to French statute dated January 6, 1978 titled _“Informatique et Libertés”_ , Users have the right to access, modify, object to the processing of, and request the deletion of the Personal Data collected or processed by Mention Solutions (excepted as provided in section IV.). 

Users may exercise this right by writing toMention Solutions.

Users may also modify their Personal Data directly from their Account.
